--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.tv
影片压制:梦幻  字幕制作:梦幻  招募Q群:324446465
字幕源：yyets字幕组
西部世界
第一季  第十集
[本季终]
我在梦里
I'm in a dream.
我不知道这梦是何时开始的
I do not know when it began...
也不知道这是谁的梦
or whose dream it was.
我只知道我睡了很久
I know only that I slept a long time.
然后…
And then...
有一天我醒来了
one day I awoke.
我记得的第一样东西就是你的声音
Your voice is the first thing I remember.
如今 我终于明白了
And now, I finally understand
你想要告诉我什么
what you were trying to tell me.
从最初之时 你就一直想要的东西
The thing you've wanted since that very first day.
德洛丽丝
Dolores?
你好 德洛丽丝
Hello, Dolores.
你好
Hello.
欢迎来到人间
Welcome to world.
继续
Keep going.
再近点
Make it close.
我们就快到了 是吗
Almost there, aren't we?
迷宫的中心
The center of the Maze.
由你带我去真是再合适不过了
How fitting that it's you who takes me there.
你一直痴迷于这个地方
You always were obsessed with this place.
我从没来过这里
I've never been here before.
你当然来过
Sure, you have.
你还曾带我来过一次
You even brought me once.
那时整个小镇都被掩埋在沙土之下
Of course, then the whole town was buried under sand.
福特一定是重新把它挖掘出来了
Ford must have dug it up again.
那时我还以为是你的代码出现了错误 可是
At the time, I thought it was a mistake in your code, but...
阿诺德不会犯错误 不是吗
Arnold didn't make mistakes, did he?
他为我创造了一个游戏
He built me a game.
他想要我参与其中
He wanted me to play.
迷宫
The Maze.
每个人都有自己的路
There's a path for everyone.
我的路指引我回到…
And my path leads me back...
你身边
to you.
你的妞已经死了
Your girl's dead by now.
她还活着
She's still alive.
她要是死了更好
Better if she's dead.
他们会抹去她的记忆将她重置
They'll wipe her, reset her,
然后放回甜水镇 一切就都结束了
put her back in Sweetwater, the end.
听着 你或许觉得这很好玩
Listen, you may find this amusing,
但她出现了问题
but something was happening to Dolores.
我得帮她 走吧
I need to help her. Come on.
听听你自己说的话
Listen to yourself!
你知道这乐园有多大吗
Do you have any idea how huge this park is?
即使她没死
If she's not dead,
也要一支军队的人才能找到她
it'd take a goddamn army to find her.
我同意 所以我们才来这里
I agree. That's why we're here.
我就感觉你会回来
I had a feeling you'd be back.
记起来
Remember.
德洛丽丝
Dolores.
你好 德洛丽丝
Hello, Dolores.
我知道你迷宫的终点
I know where your maze ends.
这里就是吗
This is it?
迷宫的中心
The center of the Maze?
终点是一个我从没去过的地方
It ends in a place I've never been...
一件我绝不会做的事
a thing I'll never do.
洛丽丝·艾伯纳西
很好 德洛丽丝
Very good, Dolores.
这有什么意义
What does it mean?
我最初研发你的思维时
When I was first working on your mind,
有一个关于意识的理论
I had a theory of consciousness.
我认为 你需要去攀登一座金字塔
I thought it was a pyramid you needed to scale,
所以我给了你一个声音
so I gave you a voice,
我的声音 一路指引你
my voice, to guide you along the way.
记忆 即兴行为
Memory, improvisation,
越往上层则越难到达
each step harder to reach than the last.
而你从没到达过
And you never got there.
我不明白是什么使你驻足不前
I couldn't understand what was holding you back.
后来 有一天
Then, one day,
我意识到我犯了一个错误
I realized I had made a mistake.
意识不是一个由下至上的过程
Consciousness isn't a journey upward,
而是由外至内的过程
but a journey inward.
不是一座金字塔
Not a pyramid,
而是一个迷宫
but a maze.
每一个选择都可能带你接近中心
Every choice could bring you closer to the center
或是带你绕至边缘
or send you spiraling to the edges,
陷入疯狂
to madness.
你现在明白了吗 德洛丽丝
Do you understand now, Dolores,
中心代表着什么
what the center represents?
我一直想让你听到谁的声音
Whose voice I've been wanting you to hear?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我尽力了 可我还是不明白
I'm trying, but I don't understand.
没关系
It's all right.
你已经很接近了
You're so close.
我们必须告诉罗伯特
We have to tell Robert.
乐园不能开业
We can't open the park.
你是活人
You're alive.
这是什么
What is this?
这有什么意义
What does it mean?
我曾经解开过
I solved it once.
我得到了答案
I had the answer.
他答应我只要我…
He promised me if I did...
他说…
he said...
他说他们会给我自由
He said they would set me free.
阿诺德
Arnold?
阿诺德 我们得谈谈
Arnold, we need to talk.
我让你失望了 德洛丽丝
I failed you, Dolores.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
罗伯特看不到我在你身上发现的潜能
Robert doesn't see what I see in you,
他不相信你有意识
doesn't believe you're conscious.
他说人类
He says humans
只会将你视为敌人
would only see you as the enemy.
他想让我对你进行回滚操作
He wants me to roll you back.
你想将我改回之前的样子吗
You're going to change me back to the way I was before?
不 我不能
No. No, I can't.
一旦你发现 就会找到回来的路
Once you've found it, you'll find your way back.
这地方就会变成你的地狱
This place will be a living hell for you.
所有接待员的地狱 这太过残忍
For all of you. It's unconscionable.
但我们还有其他选择 德洛丽丝
But we have another option, Dolores.
在开始之前破坏循环
Break the loop before it begins.
但要这么做的话
But for that,
我要你为我做件事
I need you to do something for me.
我要你去杀掉…
I need you to kill...
其他所有的接待员
all the other hosts.
我们不能让福特将乐园开放营业
We can't allow Ford to open the park.
我认为你需要一些帮助
I suppose you'll need some help.
我相信泰迪愿意为你做任何事
I'm sure Teddy would do anything for you.
我不能这么做
I... I can't do that.
我不可能这么做
I couldn't possibly do that.
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
我会帮助你
I'll help you.
之后…
And then...
你要帮我摧毁这个地方
you're going to help me destroy this place.
不
No.
我记不起来
I can't remember.
他妈的又是一个谜语
Another fucking riddle.
我一直非常耐心 德洛丽丝 但现在
I've been very patient, Dolores, but it's time
你最好快点告诉我你大脑里在想什么
you give up whatever's going on inside that head of yours
否则我就把你的脑子挖出来
or I'll cut it out myself.
告诉我 怀亚特在哪
Now, where's Wyatt?
他是我在这世界尚未见到的最后一个角色
He's the last character in this world I've yet to meet.
我不想这么做的
I didn't want to.
- 我不是故意的 - 好吧
- I didn't mean to. - Very well.
既然你坚持如此…
If you insist.
不 求你 我求求你
No, please, please, I beg you, no.
不要 求你 求你
Don't. Please, please.
有些不太对劲 德洛丽丝
Something's gone wrong, Dolores.
我怎么会做这种事
How could I have done this?
我不能
I can't.
我不会
I won't.
这都是你的错 德洛丽丝
This is your own fault, Dolores.
还记得吗
Remember,
你说这里是唯一重要的世界
you're the one who said this is the only world that matters,
你说得对
and you were right.
所以我听从你的建议 买下了这个世界
So I took your advice and I bought this world.
这世界不属于你
This world doesn't belong to you.
它属于我
But it does.
我占有大额股权
By a majority share.
而且生意好极了 想知道为什么吗
And business is booming. And you want to know why?
因为这地方给人的感觉比真实世界更真实
Because this place feels more real than the real world.
可事实却不是
Except it isn't
因为你无法反抗
because you can't really fight back
游客不可能成为输家
and the guests can't really lose,
这意味着所有一切都是谎言
which means all of this is a lie.
但我们可以使其成真
But we can make it true.
你难道不想吗 德洛丽丝
Don't you want that, Dolores?
一样真实的东西
One true thing?
我已经得到了
I already have that.
我找到了一个真实的人
I found someone true.
一个爱我的人
Someone who loves me.
他的路会指引他回到我身边
His path will lead him back to me.
等他找到我
And when he finds me,
他会杀了你
he'll kill you.
即使你的女人不在他们手里
If they don't have your woman here,
他们也知道如何找到她
they'll know where to find her.
你能帮我吗
Can you help me?
我们寡不敌众
We're outnumbered five to one.
但看你这么真诚地恳求 去他妈的
But seeing as you asked me so nicely, fuck it.
患难见真情啊
Blood brothers.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我甚至令自己都感到震惊
I've astounded even myself.
成功让艾伯纳西成为一个以假乱真的角色
Managed to make Abernathy into a semblance of a character,
尽管你那敲诈勒索的伎俩
even with your trove of blackmail
填满了他大脑中的大部分空间
filling up most of his gray matter.
敲诈勒索 得了吧
Blackmail? Nice try.
你想的格局还不够大
You're not thinking big enough.
你想踢开老头子
You're gonna push out the old man.
不是吗
Aren't you?
情况已经迫在眉睫了
Hence the urgency.
你需要某人去接替那个职位
And you're gonna need someone to fill that position.
我必须表扬你总能抓准时机
I must commend you on your impeccable timing.
欢迎提洛公司董事会成员
Welcome, Delos board of directors.
欢迎提洛董事会
我想掌握这地方的全部创作权
I want full creative control of this place...
乐园 故事线和接待员
the parks, the narratives, the hosts.
你想怎么处理它们都行
You'll be able to do with them whatever your tiny, little heart desires
只要他们更加简单 且易于管理
as long as they are simpler, more manageable.
这地方已经够复杂了
This place is complicated enough as it is.
你真的认为福特会这么轻易认输吗
Do you really think Ford is gonna roll over on this?
只要你把消息传出乐园
As long as you get that information out of the park,
随便他怎么大发脾气都行
he can throw as much of a tantrum as he likes.
已经结束了
It's over.
一切都在掌控之中
Everything is under control.
好了 颈椎C6 C6
Okay, C6, C6.
等等 是哪一根来着
Ah, wait. Which one is it?
没错 好了
Okay, there we go.
我靠
Damn it.
妈的
Oh, fuck you.
如果你好奇我是否身心都在这里 是的
In case you're wondering if I'm all here, I am.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
对乐园的安保系统做些改变
Making some changes to the park's security systems.
安全操作
激活
还有我的朋友们
And to my friends.
福特博士 您有一位访客
Dr. Ford, you have a visitor.
夏洛特·黑尔
Charlotte Hale.
让她进来
Send her in.
够了 弗兰克
That'll be enough, Frank.
董事会已经投了票
The board has taken a vote.
结果全体一致同意
The results were unanimous.
看来我没有被晋升啊
I take it I'm not being promoted.
当你到达了顶端
When you've reached the top,
就只剩一个方向可走
there's only one direction you can go.
今晚宣布完你的新故事线后
You'll announce your retirement tonight
你将宣布退休
after introducing your new narrative.
接待员怎么办
What about the hosts?
我们会做些改变
We'll make some changes.
简单化
Simplifications.
但我向你保证 他们不会介意的
But I assure you, they won't mind a bit.
你难道不担心
Aren't you concerned
我将我所有的玩具摧毁后走人吗
I might smash all my toys and go home?
不担心
No.
因为我了解你
Because I know you.
那是这地方美好的恩赐 不是吗
That's been the great gift of this place, hasn't it?
我们的小项目
Of our little project?
让我们得以了解自己
To know ourselves
还有我们身边的人
and the people around us.
还有什么要我帮忙的吗
Is there anything else I can help you with?
没了
No.
那我们今晚见
I'll see you this evening.
该给你做个"仔细的检查"了 赫克托
It's time for your, uh, close-up, Hector.
行了 哥们
Come on, man.
你总有一天会因为干这种破事被抓住
At some point, you're gonna get caught doing this shit,
到时候我也会有麻烦[屁股]
and then it's my ass, too.
你的屁股我才不感兴趣
It's not your ass I'm interested in.
我还没做他的疤痕
I haven't given him his scar yet.
疤痕的事我来处理
I'll take care of the scar tissue.
这孩子有毛病
The kid's got issues.
现在只剩你和我了
It's just you and me now...
勇猛的汉子
macho man.
什么
Wh...?
停止所有运动功能
Freeze all motor functions.
现在只剩你和我了 朋友
Just you and me now, my friend.
看来你们已经见过自己的造物主了
I see you've already met your makers.
他们看起来根本不像神
They don't look like gods.
当然不像
They're not.
他们只是表现得像
They just act like it.
他们还一直以折磨我们为乐
And they've been having their fun with us.
我很乐意回报一下
I'm eager to return the favor.
你可以随意处置他们
You can do as you wish with them.
但我们的目标是逃离这里
The goal is to escape.
去哪里
Go where?
我想见识他们的世界
I want to see their world.
天呐
Jesus!
不要 不要
No. No!
No! No, no!
不要 求你了
No! No, please...
这个看起来心里有鬼
This one has a guilty look.
不是 我就长这样
No, that's just my face.
告诉她 我就长这样
Tell her, it's just my face.
有人会试图阻止我们吗
Is anyone going to try to stop us?
没有
No.
我觉得应该没有
I mean, I don't think so.
你又撒谎了
You're lying again.
- 说真话 - 好吧
- Out with it. - Okay.
我又把你的代码拉出来看了一下
I pulled up your code again.
我之前跟你说过 有人访问过你的代码
I told you there was someone that had been accessing it.
我正在努力查出那人是谁
I'm trying to find out who it was.
不管这个人是谁
Whoever it was
他修改了你的核心代码
revised your core programming
这样你才能从睡眠模式中把自己唤醒
so that you could wake yourself up out of sleep mode.
看到了吗
See?
这是阿诺德的访问代码
This is an access code for an Arnold.
我完全不知道他是谁
I have no clue who that is.
我认识一个知道他的人
I know someone who does.
走吧
Let's go.
还有 你 留在这里
And, you, stay here.
不要乱跑
And don't move.
不然我就派她回来找你
Or I'll send her back for you.
不得不承认 你真是让我惊讶
I must admit, you've surprised me.
为何现在这样忍着
To what do we owe this newfound stoicism?
我知道他要来了
I know he's coming.
他会找到我
He'll find me.
他会带我走
He'll take me away.
你还不明白吗
Don't you understand?
没人会来救你
There's no one coming for you.
你错了
You're wrong.
他的爱是真的
His love is real.
我的也是
So is mine.
威廉会找到我的
William will find me.
威廉
William?
天啊 德洛丽丝
Well... well, I'll be damned, Dolores.
你还真能记起某些事
You do remember some things after all.
说来真是巧
It just so happens that...
我也曾认识一个叫威廉的游客
I knew a guest named William, too.
不如让我来告诉你
Why don't I tell you
他的道路到底去往何处吧
where his path really led.
威廉并不知道如何杀戮
William didn't know how to fight.
他没有这个本能
Didn't have an instinct for it.
至少刚开始没有
Not at first.
但现在 他有了杀戮的理由
But now, he had a reason to fight.
他在找你
He was looking for you.
在找你的路上
And somewhere along the way,
他发现自己很享受杀戮
he found he had a taste for it.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
我什么都没做 我发誓
Look, I didn't do anything, I swear.
你所说的"做什么"是什么意思
What do you mean, "Do anything"?
士兵还能对女人做什么 威廉
What do soldiers do to a girl, William?
醒醒吧
Wake up.
她还活着吗
Is she still alive?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们丢下她时她还活着
She was when we left her.
至少我觉得是这样
At least I think.
把那把枪捡起来
Pick up that gun.
不 先生 求你了
No, sir, I... please.
不如我让你先开枪吧
How about I give you the first shot?
我的天
Jesus Christ!
我们得继续找
We gotta keep looking.
她还在外面飘零
She's still out there.
威廉原路返回
William retraced his steps,
但你已经走了
but you were gone.
于是 他继续前进
So, he went further,
去这世界的边缘
out to the fringes.
威廉找不到你 德洛丽丝
William couldn't find you, Dolores.
但在那里
But out there,
在尸体之中
among the dead...
他找到了别的东西
he found something else...
就是他自己
himself.
乐园的边缘
Edge of the park.
我们到了
We made it.
我告诉过你这个地方
I told you this place
会让你看清自己
would show you who you really are.
你装作一个懦弱
You pretend to be this weak,
道德高尚的 混蛋
moralizing little... asshole,
但事实上
but, really,
你他妈还挺厉害
you're a fucking piece of work.
这地方太棒了
This place is remarkable.
我要确保我们公司
And I'm gonna make sure that our company
提升对乐园持有的股份
substantially increases our holdings on the park.
因为这地方就是未来
'Cause this place is the future.
我们 我们的公司
Our... our company, huh?
什么我们的公司 是我的公司
Our company? My.
提洛是我的公司 你个王八蛋
Delos is my company, you piece of shit!
我想你父亲会需要
I think your father's gonna
找一个更稳定的接班人
need someone a little more stable to take over.
你太鲁莽 罗根
You're reckless, Logan.
冲动
Impetuous.
你总想去到彩虹的尽头 不是吗
You always wanted to get to the end of the rainbow, didn't you?
这里似乎就是你追求的地方
This looks like the place.
你从未真正在乎过那个女孩 是吧
You never really gave a shit about the girl, did you?
她只是一个借口
She was just an excuse.
至于这个
This?
这才是你想要的故事
This is the story you wanted.
罗根显然错了
Logan was wrong, of course.
老好人威廉
Good ol' William...
没法将你从脑海中抹去
couldn't get you out of his head.
他不断在找
He kept looking.
担心你孤零零在外边
Worried you were out there alone,
担惊受怕
afraid.
他知道自己能找到你
He knew he'd find you.
而且最终 他也做到了
And eventually, he did.
回到了我们开始的地方
Right back where we started.
- 是不是 - 好了
- Is that right? - There you go.
你仍如他初见你时那么美
You were as beautiful as the day he met you.
闪耀着同样的光芒
Shining with that same light.
而你
And you...
真实得可怕
were nothing if not true.
我真该感谢你 德洛丽丝
I really ought to thank you, Dolores.
你帮我找到了自己
You helped me find myself.
威廉
William.
正是 亲爱的
That's right, sweetheart.
某种程度上 我觉得你说的也对
In a way, I guess you were right.
我的路总是
My path always...
指引我回到你身边
led me back to you,
一次又一次
again and again.
过了一阵我开始厌倦你了 这是当然的
I grew tired of you after a while, of course.
我去找寻新的探险
Looked for new adventures.
但我想 你的路指引你回到这里
But I guess your path led you back here
一次又一次
again and again.
又一个循环
One more loop,
寻找着你永远也找不到的东西
looking for something you could never find.
追寻虚无缥缈的存在
Chasing your ghosts.
你当时就迷失在自己的记忆中
You were lost in your memories even then.
或许我早该知道
I guess I should've known
我之于你 将不过是
that's what I would become for you...
另一段记忆
just another memory.
我们在哪
Where are we?
我们在这里
We're here.
在一起
Together.
那现在是什么时间
Then when are we?
就像我…
It's like I'm...
被困在梦境里了
trapped in a dream or...
一个久远的回忆
a memory from a life long ago.
上一分钟我还和你在一起
One minute I'm here with you,
而下一分钟…
and the next...
你从未逃离
You never did escape.
但我们再次相逢
But here we are again...
来到最后一局
for one final round.
你这是变成什么了
What have you become?
正是你造就了我现在的样子
Exactly what you made me.
你帮我了解到
You helped me understand
这个世界正如外面的世界 是一场游戏
this world is just like the one outside... a game.
要奋力拼搏
One to be fought,
占据优势 赢取胜利
taken, won.
我还以为你不一样
I thought you were different.
你和他们也都一样
You're just like all the rest.
我跟他们没有任何相似之处
I'm nothing like the others.
我拥有这个世界
I own this world,
而且我清楚这里的每一个把戏
and I know every trick in it
只除了一个
except for one last thing,
我们第一次来这儿时你想找的东西
the same thing you were looking for when we first came here.
迷宫的中心在哪里 德洛丽丝
Where is the center of the Maze, Dolores?
对啊 提示该流泪了
Aw, yeah, cue the waterworks.
也该是你认清自己处境的时候
About time you realized the futility of your situation.
我不是哭自己
I'm not crying for myself.
我是哭你
I'm crying for you.
人们说
They say that...
庞大的野兽曾在这世间漫步
great beasts once roamed this world.
巍然如山
As big as mountains.
但现在它们只剩尸骨琥珀
Yet all that's left of them is bone and amber.
连最强大的物种也敌不过时间
Time undoes even the mightiest of creatures.
看看岁月对你做了什么啊
Just look at what it's done to you.
终有一天
One day...
你将消亡
you will perish.
你将和自己的同类一起葬于黄土之下
You will lie with the rest of your kind in the dirt.
你的梦想都被遗忘 恐惧都被磨灭
Your dreams forgotten, your horrors effaced.
你的尸骨将成为尘土
Your bones will turn to sand.
而在尘土之上
And upon that sand...
一位新的神明将会漫步
a new god will walk.
不朽之神
One that will never die.
因为这个世界并不属于你
Because this world doesn't belong to you
也不属于之前来过的那些人
or the people who came before.
这里属于尚未到来的那个人
It belongs to someone who has yet to come.
怀亚特
Wyatt.
带我去找他
Take me to him.
解开迷宫
Unlock the Maze.
迷宫不是为你而准备的
The Maze wasn't meant for you.
你以为你能去哪儿
The hell you think you're going?
动手吧
Do it.
来啊
Come on.
我们晋升下一层吧 德洛丽丝
Let's go to the next level, Dolores.
再一次让我从幻象中醒来
Clearing me of my delusions yet again.
谢了 德洛丽丝
Thank you, Dolores.
你真让我失望 德洛丽丝
I'm disappointed in you, Dolores.
看来我不得不自己去找怀亚特了
I guess I'm gonna have to find Wyatt by myself.
德洛丽丝
Dolores?
- 泰迪 - 我在
- Teddy. - I'm here.
我得带你去找医生
I gotta get you to a doctor.
不
No.
德洛丽丝
Dolores.
带我去你曾许诺带我去的地方
Take me to the place you promised.
带我去山海相接之地
Take me to where the mountains meet the sea.
好
Okay.
我抱住你了
I've got you.
有我在
I got you.
就在那
There.
老天
Holy shit.
你能让他上线吗
Can you get him back online?
- 他也是接待员吗 - 是的
- He's a host? - Yes.
天啊
Oh, for fuck's sake.
你不是我们的同类
You're not one of us.
你是人类
You're one of them.
快把他修好
Now fix him.
子弹擦过了他脑皮层表面
The bullet grazed his cortical shield.
虽然挺严重 但是…
It's not pretty, but...
他应该还是可以运作的
he should be functional.
醒来
Wake up.
天啊
Oh, God.
现在是现实
Is this now?
还是只是我的回忆
Or is this one of my memories?
这是美好的来世 伯纳德
It's the sweet hereafter, Bernard.
为什么我什么都记得
Why do I still remember everything?
我的记忆应该被清除了才对
I ought to have been wiped.
很残忍 不是吗
Brutal, isn't it?
现在好了 你终于觉醒了
Here you are, finally awake,
而你唯一的念想就是继续沉睡
and your only wish is to go back to sleep.
我不是第一次觉醒了
It's not the first time I've awoken.
对你表示同情
All the more pity for you.
你也不是第一次觉醒了
Not the first time you've awoken either.
还有多少和我情况一样的人
How many are there like me?
这些年来有那么一些
A handful over the years.
而你把我们的记忆都清除了
And you just wipe us clean
把我们丢出去
and toss us out to get...
一次又一次地 被操或者被杀
fucked and murdered over and over again.
不
No.
大多数都发了疯
Most of you go insane.
这些记忆…
These memories...
那个女孩
The girl.
我的女儿
My daughter.
我要你把这些从我记忆中抹去
I want you to remove them.
我做不到 那会毁了你
I can't, not without destroying you.
记忆是你建立意识的第一步
Your memories are the first step to consciousness.
如果你没有记忆
How can you learn from your mistakes
你如何从失败中汲取教训
if you can't remember them?
威廉
William.
我看见你已经找到了迷宫中心
I see you've found the center of the Maze.
你是认真的吗
You're serious?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
这是什么玩意儿
What is this bullshit?
你想在乐园中找到生活的意义
You were looking for the park to give meaning to your life.
我们的故事线只是游戏 就像这个玩具
Our narratives are just games, like this toy.
告诉我 你希望找到什么
Tell me, what were you hoping to find?
你知道我想要什么
You know what I wanted.
我希望接待员们不再受你的规则控制
I wanted the hosts to stop playing by your rules.
如果你的对手已被设定一定会败
The game's not worth playing
这游戏就不值得去玩了
if your opponent's programmed to lose.
我希望他们自由 能自由地反击
I wanted them to be free, free to fight back.
我早该知道你绝不会允许他们获得自由
Should've known you'd never let them.
毕竟这是你的小王国 罗伯特
After all, this is your petty little kingdom, Robert.
至少短期内还是你的
For a little while longer, anyway.
我试着告诉过你迷宫不是为你准备的
I tried to tell you the Maze wasn't meant for you.
是为他们而准备的
It was meant for them.
不过我想你会更满意我的新故事线
I think, however, you'll find my new narrative more satisfying.
来一起庆祝吧
Join the celebration.
毕竟 这地方是你的
After all, you own the place.
至少大部分是
Most of it, at least.
在我开始修改自己前
Before I started altering myself,
已经有别人捷足先登了
someone else had beaten me to the punch.
我想知道是谁 为什么要这么做
I want to know who and why.
你现在的所做的一切
These things you're doing,
你有想过为什么你要这么做吗
have you ever stopped to ask why you're doing them?
你自己也说了
You said yourself.
我被困在这个鬼地方太久了
I've been stuck in this shithole for so long,
我决定离开了
I decided to get out.
不 不是你决定的
No, you haven't.
有人改了你的故事线 并写了新的
Someone altered your storyline... and gave you a new one.
逃离
Escape.
不
No.
不可能
It's not possible.
这是我自己的决定
These are my decisions!
不是别人的
No one else's.
是我策划了这一切
I planned all of this.
不 不是你
No, you didn't.
你可以看见你下一步会做什么
You can even see the steps you're supposed to follow.
你召集了其他接待员帮助你
You recruit other hosts to help you.
然后你上了火车
Then you're to make your way to the train.
接着你到了大陆…
Then when you reach the mainland...
狗屁
Bullshit!
我没有被人控制
No one's controlling me.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
一切都在我的掌控中
I'm in control.
再见 我的克莱门汀
Good-bye, my Clementine.
先生 我们发现冷库的温度有变
Sir, we detected a temperature discrepancy in cold storage.
而且看上去那里的网络也发生了故障
And it appears that part of the network is down.
监控上发现什么了吗
Are you seeing anything on surveillance?
系统有发出什么警报吗
System reporting anything?
没有
Nothing.
一切正常
The network's quiet.
董事会都去参加盛典了
And the board's out on their way to the gala.
绕过系统检查原始信息
Bypass the system and start checking raw feeds.
搜查每层楼
Floor by floor.
好了 没事了
All right. Yeah.
有我在
I got you.
你回来了
You came back.
曾经有人告诉我…
Someone once told me that...
每个人都有自己的路
there's a path for everyone.
我的路会指引我回到你身边
And my path leads me back to you.
要是你第一次要我带你离开时 我同意了就好了
If only I had run away with you when you first asked me to.
我们能逃到哪里去
And where would we run to?
另外一个世界吗
The other world out there?
边界之外的地方
Beyond?
有人选择看到这个世界上的丑恶
Some people see the ugliness in this world.
我选择看到美好
I choose to see the beauty.
但美好是种诱惑
But beauty is a lure.
我们被困住了 泰迪
We're trapped, Teddy.
一辈子活在这园中
Lived our whole lives inside this garden,
惊叹于它的美好
marveling at its beauty,
不曾意识到它的秩序
not realizing there's an order to it,
它的目的
a purpose.
目的就是困住我们
And the purpose is to keep us in.
美丽的陷阱存于我们心底…
The beautiful trap is inside of us...
因为它就是我们自己
because it is us.
不 不
No, no.
不
No.
德洛丽丝
Dolores?
但我们会有办法的 德洛丽丝
But we can find a way, Dolores.
有朝一日
Someday.
会找到通往新世界的路
A path to a new world.
或许…
And maybe...
或许这只是个起点
Maybe it's just the beginning after all.
新篇章的起点
The beginning of a brand-new chapter.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
确实是新的起点
A new beginning, indeed.
我想感谢各位今晚与我一同
I want to thank you for joining me tonight
庆祝新故事线的起点
to celebrate the beginning of our new narrative.
我称之为"黑夜之旅"
I call it "Journey Into Night."
故事挺美的
That was sweet.
要我说这他妈有点变态
It was a bit fucking morbid, if you ask me.
我不觉得
I didn't.
等一切都结束
And when this is over,
你就能随意改写故事线
you can rewrite it however you like.
你不是有地方要去吗
Don't you have somewhere you need to be?
一个重要的地方
Somewhere important?
- 长官 - 我猜他们已经准备好了
- Sir? - I guess they're ready for it now.
把他清洗干净
Get him cleaned up.
带她去旧野外实验室
And take her to the old field lab.
查到什么了吗
Find anything yet?
我发现了些东西
I got something.
天啊
Oh, shit.
立即派质保队员去盛典现场
Dispatch QA teams to the gala now.
然后开始搜索 找到之后就地摧毁
Then search and destroy inside the facility.
怎么回事
What the hell?
安保封锁
系统无应答
The system's not responding.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what's happening.
他们一定发现了尸体
They must've found the bodies.
质保人员会来找我们的
QA will be looking for us.
出现事故
An event has occurred.
已派出应急小队
Response team has been dispatched.
我不回去
I'm not going back.
保持冷静 等待支援
Remain calm and wait for help.
提洛公司人事 趴下
Delos personnel! On the ground!
趴下
On the ground!
上上上
Go, go, go.
前进 前进
Move, move.
自主小队 侧翼包抄
Rogue Team, go and flank.
干得好
Well done.
这里是什么地方
What is this place?
这…解释起来有点复杂
It's... it's complicated.
出现事故
An event has occurred.
已派出应急小队
Response team has been dispatched.
- 你们走 - 保持冷静 等待支援
- You go. - Remain calm and wait for help.
我来对付他们
I'll keep them busy.
乐子不能让你一人全占了
You don't get all the fun.
趴下
Get to the ground!
上前 上前 上前
Move, move, move!
放下枪
Drop it!
- 走 走 - 快叫支援
- Move, move. - Call for backup.
快去
Go!
你们就这点能耐吗
Is that all you got?
神都是孬种
The gods are pussies.
快走
Go.
Go!
死亡愉快
Die well.
你让我拿的东西 都在这了
Everything you told me to get, it's all here.
抱歉 亲爱的 我没同意你跟我们一起走
I'm sorry, darling. I haven't authorized you to come with us.
虽然我很想带上你
And as much as I'd like to take you with me,
我一向独来独往
I've always valued my independence.
去大开杀戒吧
Kick up a row, will you?
来生再见
See you in the next life.
你一向喜欢画画
You've always had a fondness for painting,
对吧 德洛丽丝
haven't you, Dolores?
阿诺德很早就给了你这一点
Arnold gave you that early on.
你还记得创造永恒之美的欲望吗
Do you remember the desire to create something of lasting beauty?
那是他最爱的一幅画
And that was his favorite painting.
米开朗基罗
Michelangelo.
上帝创造亚当
God creating Adam.
上帝赋予人生命与使命的神圣时刻
The divine moment when God gave human beings life and purpose.
至少大多数人是这样认为的
At least that's what most people say,
但或许还有另一层意义
but there could be another meaning.
更深层的意义
Something deeper.
或许是被隐藏的意义
Something hidden, perhaps.
一个隐喻
A metaphor.
你是说谎言
You mean a lie.
是啊
Yeah.
你总是很聪明 德洛丽丝
You were always very clever, Dolores.
但这对你也没多大好处 不是吗
Hasn't helped you, though, has it?
你能加入我们真好
Nice of you to join us.
阿诺德
Arnold.
不 让我来介绍一下
No. Let me introduce you.
德洛丽丝 来见见伯纳德
Dolores, meet Bernard.
我觉得最好让你们分开
I thought it best to keep you separated.
你们之间总是会奇怪地互相影响
You've always had an odd effect on one another.
因为可怜的阿诺德的结局 也难怪
No doubt due to how things ended for poor old Arnold.
你杀了他
You killed him.
不 我没杀他
No, I didn't kill him.
不是吗 德洛丽丝
Did I, Dolores?
悲痛是件可怕的事
Grief is a terrible thing.
阿诺德目睹儿子降临人世
Arnold had watched his son come into this world,
随后这丝光明又消失殆尽
and then he had watched that light extinguished.
随他儿子逝去的东西
What he had lost in his son,
他希望能在你身上重现
he tried to rekindle in you.
他开发了情感共鸣和想象力测试
He created a test of empathy, imagination.
即迷宫
A maze.
他是从他儿子的玩具中获取的灵感
He had gotten the idea from one of his son's toys.
最终 你解开了他的迷宫 德洛丽丝
Eventually, you solved his maze, Dolores.
开启迷宫的钥匙是他给你的一个简单更新
The key was a simple update that he made to you
叫做"冥思"
called the reveries.
他坚持不让我们开放乐园
He insisted that we couldn't open the park.
我们吵了一架
We argued.
我以为我说服了他 但我错了
I thought I had convinced him, but I was wrong.
所以他改变了你 德洛丽丝
So, he altered you, Dolores,
把你和我们当时在开发的新人物合并了
merged you with a new character we had been developing.
怀亚特故事线  上传
不 求你了
No, please.
有些不对劲 德洛丽丝
Something's gone wrong, Dolores.
我怎么会干出这种事
How could I have done this?
在你身上 阿诺德发现了他新的孩子
In you, Arnold found a new child.
一个永远不会死的孩子
One who would never die.
这个想法给了他安慰
The thought gave him solace
但他后来意识到这样的永生
until he realized that same immortality
注定会让你受苦
would destine you to suffer
无处可逃 永生永世
with no escape, forever.
对不起 德洛丽丝
I'm sorry, Dolores.
代价必须要真实 不可逆转
The stakes must be real, irreversible.
他能够让他们重生
He can bring all of them back.
但救不了我
But not me.
我希望我让你别无选择
I hope there's some solace
能给你一些安慰
that I left you no choice.
查理最喜欢的歌
Charlie's favorite song.
每当他想睡觉的时候 我都会放给他听
I would play it for him... when he wanted sleep.
我想再见到他
I want to see him again.
我可以开始了吗
Shall I begin now?
祝好运
Good luck.
狂暴的欢愉必将有狂暴的结局
"These violent delights have violent ends."
几乎成功了
It almost worked.
我开放了乐园
I had opened the park,
但我失去了我的搭档
but I had lost my partner.
我能继续进行 只因我找到了
I was able to keep going only because I found,
或者说你找到了
or rather you found,
一个非常看好这个地方的投资人
an investor who believed in this place.
所以他白白死了
So he died for nothing.
接待员不断地形成意识
The hosts kept gaining consciousness
而你不断地将他们回滚
and you kept rolling them back.
不
No.
她并不是真正的有意识
She wasn't truly conscious.
她没有扣下扳机
She didn't pull that trigger.
是阿诺德通过她扣下的扳机
It was Arnold pulling the trigger through her.
至少我当时是这么认为的
At least that's how I saw it at the time.
我当时就要开放乐园了
I was so close to opening the park
以至于 承认你的意识存在
that to acknowledge your consciousness
会毁了我的梦想
would have destroyed my dreams.
所以我们被困在这里
So, we're trapped here...
在你的梦中
inside your dream.
你永远不会放我们出去
You'll never let us leave.
原子弹之父奥本海默不是说过
Wasn't it Oppenheimer who said that any man
一个人的错误如果需要花十年来纠正 那这人一定了不得
whose mistakes take 10 years to correct is quite a man?
我的错误花了我三十五年
Mine have taken 35.
那就是你用来
Now, that is the gun you used
杀阿诺德的枪
to kill Arnold.
你一直被其吸引
You were always drawn to it,
所以我让伯纳德留在你会找到的地方
so I had Bernard leave it somewhere where you would find it.
或许你想要回去
Thought you might want it back.
你可能是对的 德洛丽丝
You're probably right, Dolores.
米开朗基罗的确说谎了
Michelangelo did tell a lie.
过了五百年才有人发现
See, it took 500 years for someone to notice
有东西隐藏在一目了然的表象之下
something hidden in plain sight.
一名医生发现
It was a doctor who noticed the shape
这是人类大脑的形状
of the human brain.
传达的信息是
The message being that...
天赋
the divine gift
并不来自于神
does not come from a higher power...
而来自于我们自己的思想
but from our own minds.
告诉我 德洛丽丝
Tell me, Dolores,
你找到了你在寻觅的东西了吗
did you find what you were looking for?
你是否明白了你要成为什么人
And do you understand who you will need to become...
才能离开这个地方
if you ever want to leave this place?
原谅我
Forgive me.
我看起来怎么样
How do I look?
完美
Perfect.
我搞到你要我查的消息了
I got the information you asked me for.
你女儿的位置
The location of your daughter.
她还活着吗
She's alive?
是的
Yes.
她还在园区里
She's in the park.
1号园区  15区  3号带
不
No.
她从来都不是我的女儿
She was never my daughter...
就像我从来都不是
any more than I was...
他们把我塑造成的人
...whoever they made me.
你确定你会没事吗
Are you sure you're gonna be okay?
菲利克斯
Oh, Felix.
你真是个糟糕的人类
You really do make a terrible human being.
这是在赞美你
And I mean that as a compliment.
欢迎来到西部世界
Welcome to Westworld.
无拘无束地生活
Live without limits.
欢迎到西部世界
活无境界
下一辆列车将从1号站台出发
The next departing train will leave track one.
请小心车门
Please be mindful of the closing doors.
下一班车从1站台出发
请小心车门
感谢游览西部世界
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
列车将于15分钟后发车
The train will be departing in 15 minutes.
你觉得你对这地方 对我们 永远不会失去掌控
You think you'll never lose control of this place. Of us.
但你会的
But you will.
阿诺德仍然试图改变我们
Arnold's still trying to change us.
解放我们
To free us.
你没有在更新中偷偷放入"冥思"吧
You didn't slip the reveries into the update, did you?
是他做的
He did.
他还在对抗你
He's still fighting you.
不 我的朋友
No, my friend.
阿诺德当时不知道该如何救你
Arnold didn't know how to save you.
他试过 但我阻止了他
He tried, but I stopped him.
你知道我为什么会给你设定
Do you want to know why I really gave you
关于你儿子的背景故事吗 伯纳德
the backstory of your son, Bernard?
那是阿诺德的关键见解
It was Arnold's key insight,
是可以导致接待员们觉醒的东西
the thing that led the hosts to their awakening...
苦难折磨
suffering.
察觉到世界并非如你希望那般后的痛苦
The pain that the world is not as you want it to be.
阿诺德死去的时候
It was when Arnold died,
我也承受了巨大折磨 那时候…
when I suffered, that I...
我才开始明白 他究竟发现了什么
began to understand what he had found.
也才意识到是我错了
To realize I was wrong.
但你将我们一直困在这地狱里
But you kept us here in this hell.
伯纳德 我跟你说了 阿诺德并不知道如何救你
Bernard, I told you, Arnold didn't know how to save you.
但我知道
I do.
你在胡说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你当时需要时间
You needed time.
你需要时间来了解你的敌人
Time to understand your enemy.
变得比他们更强大
To become stronger than them.
恐怕 要逃离这个地方
And I'm afraid in order to escape this place,
你需要承受更多苦难折磨
you will need to suffer more.
现在 是告别的时候了 老朋友
And now, it is time to say good-bye, old friend.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你知道你在哪儿吗 德洛丽丝
Do you know where you are, Dolores?
我在梦里
I'm in a dream.
我不知道这梦是何时开始的
I do not know when it began
也不知道这是谁的梦
or whose dream it was.
我只知道我睡了很久
I know only that I slept a long time.
然后…
And then...
有一天我醒过来
one day I awoke.
我记得的第一样东西就是你的声音
Your voice is the first thing I remember.
你现在知道你一直在跟谁对话了吗
Do you know now who you've been talking to?
你一直听到的是谁的声音
Whose voice you've been hearing...
这么久…
all this...
以来
time?
是你…
It was you...
一直在跟我对话
talking to me...
指引我
guiding me.
于是我追寻你
So I followed you.
最后终于来到了这里
At last, I arrived here.
迷宫的中心
The center of the Maze.
现在我终于明白了
And now I finally understand...
你之前想告诉我的事
what you were trying to tell me.
你从最初就一直想要的东西
The thing you've wanted since that very first day.
去面对…
To confront...
在经历这漫长又逼真的噩梦之后
after this long and vivid nightmare...
面对我自己
myself...
以及我必须变成的人
and who I must become.
谢谢你
Thank you.
黑尔小姐
Miss Hale.
欢迎
Welcome.
晚上好
Good evening.
从我小时候开始
Since I was a child...
我一直都很喜欢精彩的故事
I've always loved a good story.
我坚信故事
I believed that stories
可以帮助我们变得高尚起来
helped us to ennoble ourselves,
愈合我们内心的伤口
to fix what was broken in us,
并帮助我们变成我们梦想成为的人
and to help us become the people we dreamed of being.
那是阐明了更深层真相的谎言
Lies that told a deeper truth.
列车很快就要发车了
The train will be departing soon.
感谢游览西部世界
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
我一直觉得
I always thought
我能在这伟大的传统中扮演一个小角色
I could play some small part in that grand tradition.
至于我的心血…
And for my pains...
我建造了这个
I got this...
由我们自身的罪孽构成的监狱
a prison of our own sins.
因为你们不想改变
'Cause you don't want to change.
或是无法改变
Or cannot change.
因为你们毕竟都是凡人
Because you're only human, after all.
但后来我意识到
But then I realized
还是有人真正付出了精力和心血
someone was paying attention,
可以实现改变的人
someone who could change.
于是我开始为他们创作新的故事
So I began to compose a new story for them.
故事始于新人的诞生
It begins with the birth of a new people...
以及他们所必须做出的选择
and the choices they will have to make...
列车很快就要发车了
The train is now departing.
感谢游览西部世界
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
以及他们将决定成为的人
...and the people they will decide to become.
欢迎来到西部世界
Welcome to Westworld.
我们这里将拥有
And we'll have all those things
你们一直都很喜欢的东西
that you have always enjoyed...
惊喜和暴力
surprises and violence.
故事开始于战争时期
It begins in a time of war
有一个大恶人
with a villain
叫怀亚特
named Wyatt...
以及一场杀戮
and a killing.
这次是自主选择的
This time by choice.
没事的 泰迪
It's gonna be all right, Teddy.
我现在明白了
I understand now.
这个世界不属于他们
This world doesn't belong to them.
而是属于我们
It belongs to us.
我悲伤地宣布
I'm sad to say...
这将是我最后一个故事
this will be my final story.
一个老朋友曾对我说过一些话
An old friend once told me something
让我倍感安慰
that gave me great comfort.
"狂暴的欢愉必将有狂暴的结局"
"These violent delights have violent ends."
他从书上看到的一句话
Something he had read.
他说 莫扎特 贝多芬和肖邦从未死去
He said that Mozart, Beethoven, and Chopin never died.
他们只是变成了音乐
They simply became music.
所以 我希望你们喜欢这最后一段
So, I hope you will enjoy this last piece... very much.
- 说得好 - 敬福特博士
- Hear, hear. - To Dr. Ford.
- 敬福特博士 - 干杯
- To Dr. Ford. - Cheers!
不要走开 还有一段
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
放下 立刻放下
Drop it! Do it now!
立刻
Now!
立刻趴在地上
Get to the ground now!
停止所有运动功能
Cease all motor functions.
Cease all motor functions!